oh wait till the red thing starts okay
YouTube and Facebook welcome to our live
board meeting I think it's number 11 at
this point and we actually have agenda
items that I put on strangely the Menace
Whaler thing got moved down and down and
down because there's actually I was like
let's have a topic that we can talk
about that isn't necessarily that so you
seem to do everything in five minutes
but now we have actual agenda items
coming you'll see but we will so our
Facebook group is growing rather rapidly
especially after we were featured in
rebel wisdom both game B but also game B
projects was actually featured as one of
those symbols they put our banner up so
therefore I think people actually both
gave me projects because game piece also
kind of hard to find cuz it but space
thing and so many game be Facebook
groups anyway we have over 200 members
now do we want to have our own criteria
for admittance maybe just some questions
that are Express why we exist as well as
you know why do you want to be here
right why do you why what's your project
or what are you interested in so they
even just gets their their you know
wheels turning um yeah any thoughts
can you fill out some what questions hmm
I think I guess the easiest one to start
with is sort of the you know do you have
a project you want to help on projects
and then I guess I'll layer down from
that is uh you know sort of was your
skill set what you know if you have a
project what are you doing the project
if you want to help with the project
what have you done what are you
interested in doing that sort of stuff
how would you name it I mean I really
wish that Facebook work differently
because we don't think we don't have
access to those questions after you've
answered them right so seriously yeah I
mean it seems to be the case so I can go
back not that I know of anyway even as a
Dominican the end go back and see what
people answer so it's like really just
an admittance part but if I also don't
know whether anyone can admit people in
our
or just the admin's because if there's a
possibility that if we have the
questions we can as we admit people copy
and paste them over to something right
so that we can say and and get the
people who are ready in there to answer
them as well
I know we've tried to have a few
questionnaires that haven't quite worked
out but yeah anyway I think having
questions is a good idea maybe Carrie
and I could work together to come up
with some because Carrie seems to want
to do more of the like back-end customer
relation management part so whatever
would facilitate that process makes
sense as well right without having too
many questions like one or two questions
to say are you in the right place okay
are you adding and are we gonna add to
yours and so I think that just
acknowledging that and then maybe with
Bentley gets here we can talk about that
as well
well the other thing I'm just gonna swim
flip this around a drill is knack is the
knack tool still thing all right we
still using that we've been using it no
one's really been like it exists but no
one's really been using it so I haven't
been oh yeah she want me to sorta like
be able to solve I update it and start
linking things so the web has a look and
there's lots of stuff there was there
but I noticed there was lots of other
stuff that's not there and I was
thinking if you wanted me to go in the
backend and maybe look after it and
Linkwood everything's supposed to go and
add things as you go in because I know
you're probably busy with other stuff as
well so just thought as a way of helping
is so they put them you know update on
the back end is it isn't great it's a
kind of all one big lump that's also
used for stuff for a wiki election and a
bunch of stuff so it's not great a lot
of it um not yet I think we're in the
process of doing like an early early
mock-up of wiki election that might like
once that's ready I might kill the the
election part of knack and that might be
purely together tech gave me projects
and then it might be easier for people
to to take it over and help
well well if you want me to maybe help
you with the together tech and maybe
start one for that and start that and
Link everything if you wanted to because
I'd be quite happy to do that
you know you know I mean because I think
that would be helpful because they like
you know my cousin oh you they've got
the Google Docs about together tech
because I'm trying to think of ways so
you know to try as I said I've watched
all your earlier
your videos or not and listened to what
you said and as I said I just want to go
in and behind getting clean open name
what everything so cuz I I feel like
unless somebody's other conversation
wait yeah they might not know to look
and when they do go to look they might
not see what you know I mean because you
might not see what I've seen which I've
seen a lot you know I mean so it I just
like to look like pull all the bits
together you know it would be nice if
there was zero expectation that anyone
watches past hours together tech oh yeah
what you did I feel like is more work
than any of us have put in rewatching
our meetings you you know what yet about
what you're trying to all bring into
being I think he needs do well I needed
to do that in order for me to find out
because I know there's something between
the log years that I absolutely love
right
and I just want to help as much as I can
and while I'm rubbish at process and
they said and matter I'm just like what
are you talking about other says I can
go up with clean or pump Thea you know
so when someone's strange you might fall
across sure my go oh what's this you
don't want to be losing that interest
you know I mean so you want to be able
to give them a place that maybe not
Facebook not anyway just out there on
the web and then they can find you that
way and then say alright okay this is
where everybody's art that's what
they've done
you know I mean sorry I'm yeah and just
kind of just I think there's a lot of
value there no commercially for people
come in and understanding what and who
we are as well as what what they can
offer and what we can offer them right
yeah you don't besides coming to these
medians and just attending the Facebook
page we don't have that but it's it is
naturally emerging right you're here
it's like a Nessa
is coming together so that's awesome the
first part we're just talking about
adding questions to our Facebook group
because we're over 200 members at the
moment and what those could look like
that nak is still a thing but it's it's
in it's not anything see what's amazing
it's in transition right so possibly
having one that's just together tech if
Kari wants to work on that figuring yeah
that process out um I don't know if
we're coming to a conclusion but oh the
other thing on the agenda item was the
customer management tool Carrie had sent
a link oh and I put it on the agenda
yes CEO don't think it's a pleat
download and is based in like I'm used
to using Drupal for the stripper ones
there and there's Joomla and what I got
I just think in terms because I know
some of the CRM tools are really
expensive right and unless you'd already
bring your loads of money and sales
teams in and that you know it's you know
for something like this it's imagine and
I'm getting together I think it would be
really good because then you can sort of
like if you're having a conversation
with somebody you know there's a group
of us that you know as I said I can help
with the admin of that as well you know
and if you're as in conversations and
people and organizations and and that'll
be able to help you for when when I said
all your projects are emerging and stuff
like that and the people who you you you
working with in the conversations you
can have in and so say like if I meet
somebody that Jubilee is talking to I'm
working together to be able to have that
conversation thread in the same place so
you can actually see so people don't
actually get spammed with they're
not interested in you know I mean and
it's just what they'd interested then
then you can find out more about what
likes dislikes what balls are out
of them you know I mean what they care
about and because I do feel with all the
conversations that your ads it is one
central place where we can keep all that
then you can find out you know likes if
I wanted to Baskerville who is that or
wella
that was so and so out against it oh I
don't know he just changed up and then
he just disappeared you know I mean so
it you know to see
connect all the networking people
together I think I think it's probably
mean good I said I was just trying to
find things that were cheap and not too
lame expensive and that's kind of the
end goal for the neck prototype is to be
able to track sort of the projects to
people and then these sort of sessions
where you say hey here's a session that
happened on you know I'm June 19th
here's all the people involved hey B hey
hey Bentley had some cool stuff to say
I'm gonna go see what else he's been in
history the group they give the
committee group that you've got right if
you have the CRM stuff where does it she
selves and then of the NOC thing does
the public face of it so then you can
put out and this is why I was thinking
about China stuff like clean up behind
us and make sure that you know if
someone was interested that beacon finds
what that he says what Marcia says well
you know what you said your project and
you know I mean so I could go and I can
do that for yes you know that's what I'd
like to do but then I feel like I'm more
useful yeah as well yeah I may be able
to make some changes to the knack thing
to let you sort of go in there and add
stuff and mm-hmm
part of the thing it was designed to
sort of let people decide what they want
of their own stuff to be public mostly
for projects we've seen I think at least
now ten did different permutations of
people joining in the being like hey
let's get a list going of all the
different projects and so we've seen
bits and pieces of that and we had a
spreadsheet I just didn't want to sort
of volunteer people who's fill the
spreadsheet to go onto the neck
obviously be so like you know if they
wanted that no I mean so what like I
just you know if you just get thrown on
there without the consent or anything
you know and like obviously but you know
go in and size you up and get everything
oh it should be and then say look we've
got this project and we're collecting
projects because I do think you need to
connect people with what to do in and
what they're interested in and then
obviously as you grow enough you can see
what sorts of areas the people are then
you know I mean like that like - I'd
like to know because we always talk
about holiday chain and currencies and
that I'd like to know the people from
game B
and it would actually involved in that
and what to do in the projects and stuff
so I think you know it I think it'd be a
good way of actually you know let me let
me tide you open and then see and then
you can have a look and then obviously
as you go along board meetings people
come along and then I can maybe going up
conversations with them after the board
meeting to you know find your dates what
Polly you know how far they've got
because I think it'd be nice when the
people who come to actually go back and
say and have a one-to-one and say right
out loud did that go up what you still
need and stuff you know I mean so I'm
that like the cleaner with the map and
the booking I think that would
definitely help because that was
honestly one of the things that made the
prototype not really take off was that
people a lot of people didn't want to
have to worry about another login you
don't have to worry about learning an
another tool but if there's somebody
sort of acting as like the go-between so
if you're the one sort of managing the
actual database and then going and
reaching out and saying hey that person
filled out a spreadsheet saying they
have a project just ping them directly
on Facebook and say hey I'm doing this
do you want to be a part of it I'll just
you know add you can list if you say yes
you have to do anything yeah yeah
they're busy doing so be good to sort
like saying oh yeah how are you doing
what progressí and are there any things
that you need or don't think we can
maybe open with or does anything we're
looking for that you might want people
to know that you're not you know I mean
so I just think that you know for me to
offer you not anything for you okay for
the CRM tool and the knack is it there
because I Gerry left with the CRM tool
and it said it can be integrated with
things like WordPress and whether nak
with her nak is one of those things yeah
I think I'm stuck with it as well and as
I said it it can be customized depended
on what what so they contact management
system you use them because I like that
I've looked at the one for Drupal but
there's also one for to learn as well so
it depended on what you use in and and
it may have a specific wiki it's them
where you would me to ask the
programmers and stuff but basically it's
just a basic downloads
and then you can vote it from whatever
site you have something wrong you know
so which what was that serum that we're
suggesting a city agenda I put a link
all right
it's called sue because jenna is linked
in the private chat
it's called it's got a room it's got a
Sun box demo type so if you go to the
site there's a demo and it'll give you a
different operating systems but you'll
let you go in and look about with it and
see whether it's useful to you
Sibbi CRM dot org
yeah that's what
someone I can't - I think so
it's must be riveting to watch
spectators although I appreciate them
okay yes I think we can probably dive
deeper into that I'll uh I'll take a
look let's see sort of what how flexible
it is and how how much we can change the
database set up to sort of skew to our
needs dragging the stuff did we'd be
interested in taking on that work it's a
tool that works for them right that the
integration and you've put in time on
knack and then figuring out this new
tool and if they can go together which
means I don't know why I'm talking
because I don't know either of those
things see it Pacific just if it makes
sense to a drill and it doesn't make
sense to carry that wouldn't make sense
it carries the one doing the work but we
also don't want someone to come in and
do all the work and then go away and not
have you know lunch I said this is why I
think the civic CRM because you can help
select members in there so so so like
the group off yeah so so like a Joe
Jubilee that leave us access to that if
I drop dead tomorrow
you'd still have access to it you know I
mean you wouldn't you know because this
is what a thing about think people that
start things and if they disappear and
then just you know I really missed it's
just like oh you know it disappears
and all that work we can't get access to
it and blardy blardy blar you know I
mean so I think it'd be useful for you
Jubilee as well because if you know you
could just you know instead of you
having spreadsheets on Google Docs and
stuff like that you could put your stuff
in there that you know we could see and
then you know and they'll keep you
nights as well you know in terms of you
speaking to and as well you know I mean
it would have to be as easy as putting
it on it - yeah yeah yes cool it seems
like it's something that we need to
download and then install on to some
kind of a server I'm not sure how ill
ities I signed up green geeks ages ago
he said by is it the main name and you
can host as many domain names as you
like and haven't done book at all with
it anyway so if you want if you need
them somewhere as long as you've got the
domain name for whatever it is you do it
I could probably host it and give you
access you know I mean if you can get
maybe one of the programmers to come and
give us a hand sort of like you know
putting the stuff on it so we could run
it from that that would be great because
as I said I haven't been using it for
ages you know so and you can have as
many domain names and you could host as
much as you like so you know I'm quite
quite happy to off with that as well and
you've actually used this before
yeah well as a self be abused Drupal and
I've tried to try to build myself a site
before Facebook user Drupal and it's
quite a good operating content
management software I think it's a lot
better than Joomla but the learning
curve is quite steep because when I what
happened to me was that I get people
giving me things right and then I was
like all week later network with all
these people I just want to talk to
people of that and then although you
know people who would do album even the
program and that the kinds of leg dip so
these out we looked at a little bit and
then you go away so I ended up having to
try install it myself
and that and it's all a question of
modules of what you need and you can
build it as you know what you need as
you go you know because that's why I
like truthful rather than the other ones
and that's what we've saw software as
well so it doesn't cost anything to
install and download the only problem I
had was it was making it look pretty
because it didn't have any CSS skills or
HTML and that whereas I could install
modules but I didn't know what I was
doing with them and I was trying to
learn I was trying to gather loads of
people while trying to live programming
skills at the same time but it was made
of you know I mean so if I've got
somebody it wasn't if it was somebody I
could talk to and say right you know I'm
having problems with this teaching or
teach me I'll sure be able to do that
and then leave you know then then I
don't need to bother them again a you
know not constantly be at them like you
know why is this not working or attend
you computed on you know I mean stupid
questions
all right yeah I think we can definitely
start looking into where the hosting is
and what sort of touch musicians we make
and actually get in there and do it
because that sounds sounds useful and
that's more actually in the world that
I'm used to operating and that's what I
different for my day job is that I
manages here okay well you'll know how
powerful it is though in terms of sort
of like collecting things well not even
data just so you know cuz you can't keep
everything can you guys you know it's
yeah
and I'm in loads of notebooks all over
the shop is okay sometimes but you know
then you can't find anything you need a
alright so what are we doing so over
like we can't necessarily do it during
this hour I'm guessing what what is why
are we setting up for either two weeks
from now next week or two eternal and
Carrie want to have a conversation
outside of this like what is what is
actually happening well well uh you know
if you want a conversation about this
they don't be quite happy to do that as
well you wanna yeah sure yeah well you
can set up something I do want to be
cautious not to take on too much more as
we are in the process of trying to make
the actual coated prototype for wiki
election and I imagine that will start
to take more time about anything else
you know I mean yeah okay
Bentley you're innocent yeah so I was
just trying to find out so they do have
hosting on the other thing and then
Kerry has an option I'm just wanting to
carry when you're saying that you can
host it are you saying that you know how
to set all that up or you need someone
with I think I just need a wee a wee bit
of help right because that would look
like for a while it's in its I call
green D as I said they make you pay for
the domain name but underneath after
name domain name you can actually set
things up yourself another as many as
you want but I would need a little bit
of help maybe sort of like installing
and if there's anybody around you
might be able a little bit about you
know yeah I yeah it's just hard to tell
kind of looking at the site that if you
don't choose their hosting options how
difficult is it it's actually no I've
seen to install a Drupal installation
it's not very difficult at all because
I've actually done it myself years ago
for as I said it just needs a bit of
help
well so I mean it says integration with
Drupal are you saying that it would use
Drupal as the full-back in and you don't
need a separate service and I may be
asking questions in a way that's not
clear but and yeah so it's like save you
set up a Drupal installation you'll be
able to install a lot and then you would
not even have to use their service you
know I mean people you don't have to you
don't have to install something else
other than Drupal from civic CRM to work
oh okay
cuz it's not clear on the website that
when they say they say just say it
integrates they didn't say that they can
use the CMS as the backend but it's
probably what they mean but they're just
not very clear I could go to the
developer Docs and maybe I'll say but
it'd take a little while to look at and
figure out because I you know I you know
when you say you have green geeks I mean
this doesn't that have a cost for
hosting well it does like I've been
paying for their yearly I paid for that
yearly $600 and what I've got a year and
to host stuff and that's it you don't
get charged for however many sites you
host of that
yeah until I mean we won't be using a
lot of resources so that'll work yeah
okay
Yeah right now I don't have any I guess
I have one running server that I could
also put it on but it's running a
different technology base so if you have
something that's compatible that'd be
easier now the green geeks pricing looks
pretty reasonable
okay yes I guess we can a carry and I
can connect I'll be just over Facebook
um to figure out where we want to take
this so that we're not all just reading
various websites while we're you know a
live stream yeah did we have other
topics on the agenda it's so the other
one before you got here was just the
Facebook group having our own criteria
maybe we want to come up with one or two
questions and then we can talk about
outsourcing pedis Valley which was my
topic because we usually don't have
things on the agenda ya know a couple
questions already or it's the jet like
what is your project or what kind of
projects are you interested in just
something that makes it kind of more
clear why we exist and do you belong
here
yeah another project or looking for one
you belong here yeah and that that'll
just filter out a lot of bots anyways so
now on our rules right now if you are a
friend of someone else
wow they may still have to answer the
questions but right now there are auto
accepted if their friend is someone
that's already in the group that's
already in the group yeah if you try and
join the group and they have at least
one friend already in the group then you
automatically join it doesn't go through
the approval queue gaming P group
doesn't do that cuz I don't Julie was a
member and I went to join and I still
had to we still go through your answer
the question this week yeah yeah so
that's one piece we have turned on that
we may want to turn off I don't know if
the if you have questions whether it's
still Auto add you or still requires you
to answer the questions and I guess it
really doesn't matter if we would it
really depends on the purpose of the
questions if it's just to filter out
bots then it'd be useful just to have
one or two questions yeah it doesn't
really matter too much what they are
but I think what you said sounded great
I think what's your project or what kind
of projects are you interested in answer
one or the other and then even links to
your project so we can because we are
the one game vplace also that projects
are allowed to join right like we let
pages and groups in the heart our human
being because it makes sense yeah and I
think you're gonna answer ask that all
and at least the first question all in
one question just say if you have a
project tell us about it if not what
type of projects are you interested in
because I don't know I guess you can
leave certain questions blank yeah
so either way then the other question is
because they go away as soon as they're
asked is this just for BOTS and then
they're in we're fine or do we want to
have a process procedure of whoever's
letting that person in copies and pastes
it to a document so we have a list of
who people are and what their projects
are coming in and then we can always ask
going back we know what ours are but for
everyone because we've 200 members it's
going to be difficult to track all of
them especially if joint projects and
very interested in helping of projects
they just joined to see what's going on
so I would suggest in track only all the
products that people proudly announced
they are creating or helping with so
yeah so how you gonna have them projects
ok so you said people have said that
they've got projects and where are you
gonna keep that then oh you just want to
he's just gonna do it for that well I
think it's to be decided here
oh yeah it's just a well Wiberg mean if
we just let them in no matter how
beautiful or horrible they answer the
questions it just goes away into the
ether and Facebook right so if we're
asking that question do we want to copy
and paste it or when you do the welcome
post each week and people choose to put
it under there then we have a record and
we can go in and later look at that um
yeah I'd rather limited just to the
welcome post I think a lot of times when
people are answering those questions
they they don't put a lot of thought
into it or at least let's let me split
this way I don't put a lot of thought I
just want to make sure I get into the
group so I'd wait till they post on that
all right sounds good
so I'm not ignoring the Facebook user or
the Facebook conversation but just as
Facebook user I'm gonna guess at Shiloh
but no quite yet there's Billy but oh
yes it's shut up hi hi Chyna alright so
Mac we already talked about that we
talked with that we'll have questions
and we will change it so it's not auto
accepts and we won't copy and paste them
but there will be a question so people
kind of know what we're all about and
what we're what they're joining for are
they in the right place are we game B no
team B's not even gay B oh so our game B
the other topic that I had on the agenda
that I announced in the projects was the
outsourcing to Venezuela which I feel
like I should have learned how to say
before coming on but I don't say it for
years oh it's gonna happen in the next
few minutes but there's something with
Danielle posted his post of looking for
four people in Venezuela I'm whines no
there was something where I was like we
all have projects we want people to work
on is there a way to kind of do
something I'm not saying I'm waiting to
it but Omni wind helps all of our
projects and helps them of course get
employed I feel that most people who
speak English and have tech as their
actual thing are employed in Venezuela
like they don't actually have but
there's people who maybe only speak
Spanish and have tech and or are like
data entry level right and speak English
and would there be a way to kind of mass
want to say mass employee but that's the
wrong create an all-new in solution
right for our projects and I am and I
have this inkling that there's gonna be
more countries like Venezuela happening
yeah do it was there a reason why he's
specifically mentioned Venezuela well
they make like 10 bucks a month from
there and so there's the possibility of
paying someone a couple hundred bucks a
month
it is decent for them and not yeah so I
I wouldn't limit it to any particular
geographic location but yeah I think
having some or as a group vetting either
individuals or contract companies
because even there's a lot of companies
that help would help manage that and I
think they're worth their money for like
a project that Adria her I are doing but
what I've never really done is gone
through and vetted those organizations
and even for some startups in my local
area that I'm mentoring but the question
always comes up so I need to I need to
hire some devs for a short small project
and I don't want to pay a lot what do I
do it'd be nice to have an answer for
them I just haven't dedicated the time
to say okay I'm gonna find either well
or both some contract individuals and
you know use them on a small project see
how they go and then maybe even there
are some organizations I can't write
what they're called the contracting
companies where we would vet a few of
those and kind of have a list of hey
these are people we know we've used so
when you're going out there on up work
or freelance you're not going to get
screwed which has happened to several
I've had funded startups in the Dallas
area that have showed me some stuff that
they got that was pretty bad and they
spent tens of thousands of dollars
and they ended up with an app that
doesn't that's not even close to working
so that would be a beneficial thing I
think to do so I guess I'm just saying
yes that was really long yes now I am
I'm looking on up work just to see like
what's out there in Venezuela and there
are where's the number the number of
matches over five pages of matches of
just people who are in Venezuela and are
in the like web and mobile and software
dev group now in my experience anybody
that's gonna be on up work they're kind
of used to like they slowly get more and
more used to charging like you know
first world Isis or Western prices or
how like I'm seeing you know 10 15 20
there's some of your charging $35 an
hour so I'm not sure if that fits with
that or for like looking at something
who's maybe not quite you know at the
level where they can get away with
charging $35 an hour but you know
there's still so in my area it's $150 an
hour so 35 is a bargain right yeah but I
think the it it's still good but if
we're talking about like hey if these
people are used to making $6 a month
then if we you know if we can figure out
something where they're making $200 a
month that's a massive increase and no
I'm not sure if that's just sort of like
more like the manual labor jobs were
like you can't outsource it you have to
be there and I don't I don't like oh
it's their government jobs pay them six
dollars a month which is not in any way
enough to live on our first standard of
living it like we're you can't live
anywhere for $6 a month right but yeah
exactly having kind of almost like I
guess like together tech employees like
one or two people that's like hey if we
paid out X amount and they were working
on wiki election and this and that but
you know and then as for as more as
needed they possibly have more people to
recruit or I just of like the go-between
that I guarantee are people who are
amazing
Tech and development but don't speak
English they can do it in Spanish right
and having someone else who's not
necessarily tech but speaks Spanish and
maybe that's the problem is you kind of
need to be apples tech on Spanish but
you know liaison they get they get much
more money probably but being able to
coordinate but that was just things
sparking he starting fires what would I
do I was in my experience and a magician
definitely might have something to say
here but tech for the most part is
English like you're coding is pretty
much always done in English so if you're
a coder I don't think I've ever met a
coder that didn't help me speak like
some English I've worked with several
developers that their English was not
sufficient to communicate with and we
needed a translator I've worked with
some companies the company that I worked
for supplied a translator companies I
didn't work for that I fired did not
supply a translator and they just had
guys that didn't speak great and they
it'd be okay if I spoke that language
but they need to be able to communicate
so there's a lot of people that can code
but can't speak in a way enough way to
do that and so I do think I do think
having someone who is really familiar
with the language is that they use
commonly is is a huge benefit that does
that to the cost but yeah it sounds like
we're starting to get like a really
narrow subset of people who were like
tech speak good English and aren't
already on something like upwork or like
doing something where they're making
reasonable money in the area and not
they six dollars a month so our so part
of this goal which I didn't see the post
but was hey there's some people that are
getting screwed so we want to help them
right so yeah if that was the goal then
I would say it would be good if we found
one person that could speak their
language and be a liaison and then they
might also help maybe even in that area
and they would help find people and as
part of our process they would be you
know
they wouldn't even have to be great
developers because it would be part of
you know growing that society and and
helping that community and that culture
grow their skills so yeah I don't know
if we have enough funding in the group I
mean it's great if they don't cost that
much but I don't know if we have it
actually enough dollars going through it
to be very impactful in that yeah it was
more also like if there was a space for
data entry right something that actually
doesn't take tech skills is more just
basic literacy but they don't speak
English
having that liaison and finding like how
do we get people jobs that we you know
can hire them for that or more and would
that help right because it's I mean
solution raising doesn't necessarily be
that process raising doesn't mean that
at the moment but wiki lection might and
Gilly bot might write like I don't yeah
yeah there's definitely a chance that
some of our projects will get to a point
it's like oh we just need every name of
every governor in the universe they turn
you know every you know a bridge for
them that's something that although I
guess up works actually changed their
pricing model since I last used it for
that but that's actually what I started
out using up work for was for scraping
government information and you could
find people for like three or four
dollars an hour but I think they've
changed their pricing now I don't think
you can get somebody under I want to say
five which is still pretty good
but if we're talking about like a
hundred hours yeah like how much is in
the video that I think Julie you need to
post it or you know Florida deliver
talking about as well and then making
six dollars a month
yeah it's broken because then they also
showed like here's you know a food car
on the street where they're selling hot
dogs for ten dollars so like you can
work for or are your price right to free
hot dogs for the month yeah yeah and
that's it that's all you get and then I
think they're talking about like
hamburgers or you know or like a full
meal is ten dollars and that type of
thing is you're like yeah that's
obviously there are people that are
making some and so it's I'm not sure
how that because it's just the
guaranteed work that that's the
government job and how many hours a
month is that I'm not sure and if
they're gonna be helping us out they
need to have some sort of internet
access right yeah that's people are and
I know also in Bennett that they part of
the reason they're in this mess as they
have subsidized oil that like their oil
tanks or shoot like they so you can fill
up your tank and go across the border
and then possibly sell it and do that's
I'm not saying you're getting people to
do that but I don't know whether
internet is kind of under that same
umbrella right whether they're like hey
or socialist country we have like yes
you get your you get free internet and
free gas but you can't afford food what
am I paying you six phone seven bucks a
month right like what actually what they
do have access to right do they have
computers and internet and they just
need to be connected with people who
have and another technology to kind of
go through which I don't know if we
could focus this down to a particular
area or group of people that we know but
there's the Amazon Mechanical Turk which
is something you'd probably also use for
scraping data but I don't know if you
could focus that towards like oh we want
to help people in this area and stuff
but just to throw it out there yeah I
don't think like that kind of has the
same limitation as up working that if
they're on there they're already making
some money like it's you know probably
somewhat reasonable and yeah I wasn't a
big fan of Mechanical Turk I tried I did
like work more just cuz it it makes
prints it was very data focused like you
could sort of build your thing I'm like
okay here's a record I want you to go
find this and do this research it would
be great for that for like something
going on finding government officials or
Amazon would fit better when you don't
care who does the work and then up works
more like I'm gonna vet this person a
little bit before they do the work and
I'll have one person doing it so it
really depends on the style of work on
what's better yeah but yeah it's it's
unlikely our projects Mechanical Turk
will work real well because it takes so
much set up and we don't need that much
data I mean you could have like one
person going in and finding the website
for every community every city
right Janna in the sphere or something
and then the other person that could go
in and then someone who could say okay
find the cities you know teachers union
or something like that you know right
yeah
and that's something where I prefer
personally to work on something like up
work so I can just keep working with the
same person and you know I can learn
like oh did person is good but when I
first started doing it I was on a
project where we hired ten people and
three of them were good like three them
actually really good results and it was
quality and like they agreed with each
other because we had multiple people
script so it's the same thing to see
like okay these people don't agree with
anyone their stuff isn't good but then
let's read that word we kept working
with them for years something's like I
mean we don't really need this it was
just me trying to like I said Starfire
its of like there is part of me that's
like we can I get 10,000 of them
together even if I don't speak their
language and have them to have a
solution raising for their own society
but that's a whole other fire to start
and not yeah because the initial post
was about using resources it's the wrong
word but using helping people who have
basically no work and they're good at
something for which there is no need
right now in that country right and it
sounded very like positive and in this
conversation we also started talking
about the work that is not paid as well
in the first world and it sounded kind
of I don't I don't have to be aware of
the difference between one and the other
right
well is it just me that my mind just
called he likes both sides of the Omni
win but you like we we need cheap labor
let's be honest we have no money and we
want no cheap labor and for them to make
a good
and be able to support their families
and how do those two needs get met and
separating them so that like we're not
conflating the two is that what you're
yeah it's just I'm kind of afraid of
from being positive and helping people
so we don't know the route of
outsourcing work that just because it's
cheaper over there it's something I had
come back with previously and it just it
wasn't very positive I'm not sure not
kind of trying to find the spot in a
Venn diagram where like the overlap and
it's like cheap labor and where that
cheap labor isn't exploitative like
where's actually still helpful to that
person like yeah and this is like the
late 90s I think that there was an
article that came out on slash dot where
like there was all this hype around like
oh we're taking advantage of the people
in India because we're paying them so
little and then they had an interview
with somebody from India that was doing
this and talking about you know how do
you feel being paid such a small amount
it's like my rent is $80 a month so if I
make $2 an hour that's great mmm well I
remember the exact numbers but ended up
being like okay it actually is like here
we it's actually good for them the only
real issue is that you know in theory
that's taking away jobs from somebody
here but if we're talking about people
like me and Bentley and anyone else
paying out of our own pocket for a
project we don't have the money to pay
somebody $50 an hour for it because then
I couldn't pay rent I mean Honore sorry
no just I hope even if it was possible
the best way of just making it happen
apart from like then doing the work
would be to duplicate what outsourcing
the idea of together tech so they do the
same thing they come together and talk
about solutions that are good for them
with all the rock
context so that's something that could
be connected to this equation as well
cheap labor yes it's nice to have but
then helping them as the title of this
of the thing and at the same time
spreading the idea of like making stuff
happen together as we discuss here so
and that's nothing different from how
normally in the world people do it so
exporting that idea as well and teaching
them how to do it this way that could be
even like the most beneficial part of
this I love that cuz it sounds like then
it might naturally emerge that they're
like hey do you have work for us we cost
less you know what I mean like there's
like just how you're helping Adriel and
Bentley do their projects I'm not saying
this because less but like that
that right it naturally emerges that
like why wouldn't I use somebody I trust
and it's here but helping them come
together in translations and that's
where I was like maybe doing a solution
raising with them even if I don't speak
like the same language like finding that
and having it be something that's more
that's not what you're saying but like
ground up their their solutions what do
they need and how can we um even with
them instead of for them or especially
if you know my experience with
outsourcing is basically one of the
corpus I worked or before when they
talked about hiring people you know Far
East the main point was yeah we need ten
of them because they cost this much and
the emphasis was on how much it costs as
opposed to you know UK programmers which
it was just bad
for many reasons but and we never and
the company never actually understood
that like a local context for them and
it was also that because we just
couldn't agree on basic things because
of the cultural differences so it was
bad and in this case there are
differences but they definitely might
and should be used know the diversity
thing they might have solutions and
ideas that we don't and we can import
that from them as well as we can let
them know about the solutions and I know
way of thinking we have so yeah that's a
mutual like cooperation which is
beneficial for all parties involved
Justin assault something emerging in my
brain of like having and this would be
for them to do but having like a house
in Venice Millia where people can come
and stay learn to code learn to become
tech workers that they can possibly be
paid to do that and then they then have
a real like a skill that can be
outsourced anywhere right that they can
outsource it's not about now you own now
we own you and you have to work for us
it's like how do you how do they empower
themselves and then empower the next
people who come through and the next
people come through and have it be a
regenerative system where people and
that they're fed and provided a house
well they're learning to code and
possibly have enough you know 100 bucks
a month to live for their families I'm
sorry to to support their families I
don't even have a hundred bucks a month
is enough but if they're getting fed
then that's any way that would be for
them to figure to figure out with that
one of my dreams so like long time was
having a worldwide network of
hackerspaces precisely houses that can
promote technical ideas and people come
together and do stuff for fun technical
stuff for fun puckered spaces yes that's
what's called without physical spaces
yes well we couldn't these days you can
virtualize pretty much everything so but
the original idea for hacker space was
just a house or like a flat of whatever
physical space full of stuff where
people could actually physically come
together and do and learn from each
other and it was not an organization
even together right okay that also helps
get around alike you know we're not sure
how available Internet is there well we
can be sure that the the hacker space
has internet and that's all we really
have to care about yeah you know and
there would have to be computers and
monitors and a lodge has but that helps
sort of alleviate that or it's like if
you kind of know it but you don't have
the resources cool you can go here and
use them and then you don't know you
don't it but you'd be getting paid and
then eventually you might be able to buy
your own coders Without Borders is way
and it was more for in Canada itself
like it's so expensive to hire people
here you know a hundred thousand dollars
a year is what you would need to pay to
compete with Google at least right but
having it be like hey you're a baby
coder right you're just graduating come
live rent-free learn and offer your
skills for six months to a year the idea
that that could work in other countries
and it could be from the ground up or
they're connected with each other but no
one's top-down you know like this is how
it works it's like hey what projects do
you want to work on what ya know whether
it's for yourself and it's for profit or
what it's what it's for interesting
because then it seems that kind of
seeing how well some of the game B
principles work in that country that's
not really that game a exactly
but just the one thing that might out
it's like maybe it's not that they are
cheap labor
maybe it's the the other way around
maybe US Canada and UK are countries
totally over long prices so and the
question is why and also the answer part
of the answer is like yeah food shelter
and the everything like bottom of the
mussels pyramid is just other priced in
some countries and therefore so don't be
nice to so that's very long far away
think but work together so so the prices
are level but so that the same standard
of living can be reasonably and easily
kept in all countries so sometimes you
see two up some countries come second a
little sorry yeah I think some of it is
just a peculiarities of different
economies interacting because not all
countries of course but and some of them
you know I do an hours with you know how
many hours do I have to work in order to
pay for my rent in my groceries that's
the same even though in one place it's
ten dollars and in that same currency in
the other place would be worth a hundred
you know a different number of hours so
it's it's just kind of a quirk of a
known undesigned
kind of an economic system then so yeah
and that is kind of evening out I mean
that's been one of the problems you know
India used to be cheap for us but it's
not and that's great for them hopefully
okay absolutely gonna fit it there
society in the dirt I think it's been
the same thing in China too as these
jobs go over there that don't
our standards it pays a lot by their
standards and so it starts to kind of
raise everyone up because now there's
more money in the local economies there
and the people who are doing it like
they're ballers over there
yeah the odors from India who are you
know in like the late 90s early 2000s
that were making pennies by our
standards were doing very well locally
it's I don't think we what Milton
Friedman kind of was saying that this is
what's going to happen though the kind
of great skipped a couple steps but yeah
some benefit yeah you know there's a lot
of it is sort of in how you actually do
it and how you treat people and the sort
of spaces that you do right listen are
there windows or there lights or is it
you know is it like a nice space to work
or is it like you know a sweatshop
that's a pretty big difference for yeah
the day-to-day you know spending 40
hours a week in a place or 60 hours a
week in a place country or even just two
hours a week in a place like if it's bad
enough you know no thanks
yeah but I think as we do hire people
how and it would be kind of hypocritical
we didn't think of an omni win yes I
think that's super important and the
impact of our dollars spend in the lives
of the people that are receiving it is
something too for us to consider yeah
and it's one of the benefits like and
that can actually kind of be one of the
selling points is hey you know if you're
if you're new at this
hey you'll be making some money which
also be an experience for people who
worked in this industry you know and
learn the terms and how things operate
and so then if you want to go to a place
like upwork and start charging you know
coals from closer to Western prices this
gets you on that road I guess we don't
have anyone else other than Pedro right
now that's willing to spend some or had
some funding regardless of where it came
from to spend right as far as I know
Daniel doesn't he think wants to move
his project forward but I don't think
he's investing you know
do you wonder if that's kind of a dollar
value thing right like if they could
spend fifty or hundred dollars a month
but if they're like I know this to get
started it's gonna be $500 a month
minimum so I'm not even gonna bother but
if are like hey could you afford fifty a
month to you know get five or ten or
however many hours of somebody's time a
month okay that might be reasonable like
I might be able to and that was what I
was like is there like if we could pool
our resources and hire one person right
so they know they have enough work was
kind of where my mind was going but if
we only have two projects and that
doesn't really work but there's
something percolating of like worker
cooperatives in each of any country that
wants to start one and beyond just a
workers cooperative where you have to
pay X amount of money like Co living
part of it like a hackerspace Cola
Dean's that they like a program they can
run together bring people together live
together and choose which projects they
work on things like our projects that
are world-changing or not right it's
things that are like I work for IBM I
work for Microsoft whatever that happens
to be they're agreeing on together but
also interconnected with one another so
that have no idea how that works and we
all speak different languages but my
guess is it with with translation and
with enough people speaking a common
Venn diagram of language right that it
actually does Spanish just never had
time what we found at me today I've
tried and that might actually be like so
for example if Eduardo wanted to act as
a translator maybe he doesn't have to
pay maybe we all chip in a bit to pay
for his part and he acts as a translator
and like that's sort of one of these
because that's an important skill set
that you know not many people in this
group have yeah and another thing to
think about if there is some sort of
like hacker space like that there is
also training people on how to do this
work as being a part of it they could
come in knowing oh yeah nothing or very
little or just a little bit and then you
know yeah I think you know it's kind of
hard to figure out how much do you pay
for that how do we make
or at their time you know all that stuff
but I feel like there's something there
that we could figure out the minutiae of
the details its interests ends like
instead of like a tech project incubator
at the tech person incubator oh yeah
that sounds great
we satirized our tunnels to the low tech
but this is my dough that the network I
know are very spoke to Jubilee above
this but this is where no other network
of people starts you know I mean so if
you stay like if we've been say like six
months down the line I've been working
with youse all on the sea on I'm stuff
we know who to us you know I mean the
we'd have all the information there to
go to maybe start something with you
know who's interested in that idea you
know I mean so so from all the work that
you have done previously having these
conversations and that I thought being
it you know implemented in the beginning
you would have known right let's send
so-and-so over there to do that for what
you know I mean so um but yeah it's all
about having the network there and know
we knew everybody yes you know I mean
I've said we just haven't had that skill
set summer and we're very good for
reassigning that to no one right like
it's like we didn't know that was needed
in our skill set and capacity to be able
to do it well happy to help you with all
of that and get that up to speed you
know I mean because I said I know
beating people you know that we're very
happy to have you we're at the hour
should we say goodbye to YouTube and
Facebook unless anyone has any closing
and someone's mentioned the polymath
factories I don't know what this is or
they just naming it for us I think they
were naming it for us Kali ma
great name all right goodbye YouTube and
Facebook